Anxing Xiao

Adaptive Computing Laboratory

School of Computing

National University of Singapore, Singapore 117417

★ anxingxiao.com Coogle Scholar

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My current research topics cover motion planning, assistive robotics, and autonomous system design. My long-term research goal is to develop intelligent robots that can infer and interact with the dynamic and open world in long-horizon tasks.

EDUCATION _

National University of Singapore

Jan 2023 - present

Ph.D. student in Computer Science, GPA: 5.0/5.0

Advisors: Prof. David Hsu

Harbin Institute of Technology, Shenzhen

Aug 2017 - Jun 2021

B.Eng. in Automation (Robotics Track), GPA: 93.08/100 (Ranking 1/70)

University of California, Berkeley

Aug 2019 - Sep 2020

Visiting Student, GPA: 3.93/4.0

Advisor: Prof. Koushil Sreenath; ICRA Best Paper Award Finalist for Service Robotics

EXPERIENCE

Robotic Perception and Intelligence Lab, SUSTech & CUHK

Aug 2021 - Jun 2022

Research Assistant with Prof. Max Q.-H. Meng

Shenzhen, China

Worked on autonomous trolley collection robots and fast Generalized Voronoi Diagrams generation.

Noah's Ark Lab, Huawei

Jan 2021 - Jul 2021

Research intern with Prof. Jianzhuang Liu

Shenzhen, China

Worked on image denoising algorithm based on Vector Quantized Variational Autoencoder and Swin Transformer.

Hybrid Robotics Lab, UC Berkeley

Mar 2020 - Mar 2021

Research intern with Prof. Koushil Sreenath

Berkeley, California

Worked on robotic guide dog and quadrupedal autonomous navigation with optimized jumping.

Publications _

[1] B. Xia, H. Luan, Z. Zhao, X. Gao, P. Xie, A. Xiao*, J. Wang*, and M. Q.-H. Meng, "Collaborative Trolley Transportation System with Autonomous Nonholonomic Robots" Accepted by International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2023.

[Paper] [Video]

- [2] Y. Chen, Z. Xu, Z. Jian, G. Tang, Y. Yangli, A. Xiao*, X. Wang*, and B. Liang, "Quadruped Guidance Robot for the Visually Impaired: A Comfort-Based Approach" International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2023. [Paper] [Video]
- [3] Z. Jian, Z. Lu, X. Zhou, B. Lan, A. Xiao*, X. Wang*, and B. Liang, "PUTN: A Plane-fitting based Uneven Terrain Navigation Framework" International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2022. [Paper] [Video] [Code]
- [4] A. Xiao*, H. Luan*, Z. Zhao*, Y. Hong, J. Zhao, J. Wang, and M. Q-H Meng, "Robotic Autonomous Trolley Collection with Progressive Perception and Nonlinear Model Predictive Control" International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2022. [Paper] [Video]
- [5] S. Gilroy, D. Lau, L. Yang, E. Izaguirre, K. Biermayer, A. Xiao, M. Sun, A. Agrawal, J. Zeng, Z. Li, and K. Sreenath, "Autonomous Navigation with Optimized Jumping through Constrained Obstacles on Quadrupeds" International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering (CASE), 2021. [Paper] [Video] Media coverage [Video Friday]
- [6] A. Xiao*, W. Tong*, L. Yang*, J. Zeng, Z. Li, and K. Sreenath, "Robotic Guide Dog: Leading a Human with Leash-Guided Hybrid Physical Interactions" International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2021. Best Service Robot Paper Finalist. [Paper] [Video] Media coverage: [Daily Mail] [New Scientist] [Tech Xplore] [Daily Californian] [Independent] [Futurism] [China Daily] [DeepTech (Chinese)]
- [7] Y. Wu, A. Xiao, H. Chen, S. Zhang, Y. Liu, "Amphibious Robot's Trajectory Tracking with DNN-Based Nonlinear Model Predictive Control", International Conference on Advanced Intelligent Mechatronics (AIM), 2020 [Paper]

SELECTED AWARDS AND HONORS _

• NUS Research Scholarship	2023
• Best Paper Award Finalist for Service Robotics at ICRA '21	2021
• Dean's Award.	2021
• First-class Undergraduate Academic Scholarship	2018-2021
• Provincial-Level Merit Student.	2019
• National Scholarship.	2018

Professional Responsibilities _

- Journal Reviewing: IEEE T-RO, IEEE RA-L, Biomimetic Intelligence and Robotics
- Conference Reviewing: ICRA '22 '23, IROS '22, ROBIO '21.
- Mentorship
 - Students

* Bingyi Xia [P.1], MS @ SUSTech	2022 - 2023
* Xuheng Gao [P.1], MS @ SUSTech	2022 - 2023
* Yanbo Chen [C.6], Undergrad @ HITsz \rightarrow MS @ Tsinghua Univ.	2021 - 2022
* Zhengzhe Xu [C.6], Undergrad @ HITsz	2021 - 2022
* Xiao Zhou [C.5], Undergrad @ HITsz	2021 - 2022

SKILLS _

- Programming: Python, C/C++, MATLAB, HTML
- Softwares & Tools: ROS, PyTorch, OpenCV, CasADi, LCM, Solidworks, Gazebo, Isaac Sim, Git, LaTeX
- Hardware: Multiple Motors and Sensors, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Basic Mechanical Design
- Sports: Table Tennis, Basketball, Soccer